Subindex build by wuyanduying Created time 14.11.03 23:38:11
*********
忍者神龟：变种世代  字幕修正: 无言独影 qq894227337
< 孩子，你们是如此非比寻常 >
You are extraordinary, my sons.
< 在这世间上绝无仅有 >
Unlike anything the world has ever seen.
< 注定要成就伟大的使命 >
Bound for greatness.
< 保护 >
Destined to protect
< 纽约的人民 >
the people of New York.
< 然而，一股黑暗势力正在崛起 >
A dark force is growing.
< 是一个名为“脚帮”的犯罪组织 >
A criminal organization known as the Foot Clan.
< 他们的名称由来是因为他们 >
So named because they step over
< 无情的把市民们践踏在脚下 >
the good people of this city with no regard.
< 他们的头目，穷凶极恶的施莱德 >
Their leader, The Shredder,
< 会找上你们 >
will come at you with ferocity.
< 会凶狠的追杀你们 >
His Foot Clan will outnumber you.
< 你们将是纽约人民的 >
The people of New York will look upon you
< 唯一的希望 >
as their only hope.
< 集中精神 >
Eyes focused.
< 刻苦修行 >
Elbows locked.
< 隐匿身形 >
Stance low.
< 要记住 >
And we begin.
< 我们的胜利 >
Be one with the blades.
< 来源于厚积薄发 >
Lead their path.
< 我知道你们急于给予敌人猛烈的回击 >
I know you are eager to answer their calls,
< 但你们尚未修成正果 >
but your training is not yet complete.
< 我们地下的世界必须保存希望的火种 >
The world below must remain your home.
< 作为你们的父亲，你们必须相信我。 >
As your father, you must trust me.
< 忍 >
Patience.
< 要忍 >
Patience.
< 现在还不是你们横空出世的时机 >
You're not yet ready to go above ground.
< 但是我坚信当你们出现于 >
But I believe when that day comes
< 世人面前的时机来临时 >
and you rise to the streets,
< 你们将横扫街头 >
you are going to be responsible
< 所向披靡 >
for amazing things.
瑞瓦德先生！
Mr. Rivetti!
瑞瓦德先生 瑞瓦迪先生，拜托你 ...
Mr. Rivetti. Mr. Rivetti, please.
我发誓你是我这辈子
You're the most persistent human
见过最顽固的人了
I've ever met in my life, I swear.
听着，我已经把我知道的所有事情都告诉警察了，明白吗？
Look, I already told the cops everything, all right?
但是也许你会有
But maybe there's a detail
疏漏的细节忘记告诉警察了
you could've forgotten to share with the police.
小甜心，我不会忘记这种事情的
Sweetheart, you don't forget something like that.
十个人光天化日从天而降
Ten guys storm in here, broad daylight,
用枪指着我们，让我们趴下，
force us to the ground at gunpoint.
然后拿走这些违禁化学品
And these are restricted chemicals.
苯乙腈和一些脱氨基
Benzyl cyanide and some deaminating agents, too.
这些东西就算你在黑市上也买不到的
You don't just buy this stuff, even on the black market.
等等, 你刚说了脱氨基? 什么脱氨基
Wait, you said deaminating agents,
这些是用于基因研究的
those are used in genetic research.
还有什么其他人...
Is there anybody else
贩卖这些化学物质吗？除了你之外
that's trafficking these sort of chemicals besides you?
沿着这个港口，还有一个类似的场所，那里戒备森严
There's one other high-security facility along this waterfront.
但他们不会像我们这样大量的搬运货物
But they don't move nearly as much cargo as we do.
奥尼尔！我们30分钟后就要上直播了，赶紧走吧！
O'Neil! We're live in 30 minutes! Come on!
呃...不、不，不， 稍等下，我马上回来
Uh... No, no, no, I'll be right back.
你在这等下，我马上就来
Please don't go anywhere. I'll be right back.
你简直就是想让我丢掉工作
Come on, you're killing me.
我是在工作啊
I'm working.
- 这根本就不是你的份内事 - 不是
That's a paying job? No.
因为我们有一个实际的支付工作
Because we have an actual paying job.
听着，你不会觉得这个城市
Look, you don't think that every crime reporter
每起犯罪都和“脚帮”有关系吧？
in the city has been trying to work this Foot Clan story?
是的，我又有了新的发现
I know that, but there is a new angle on this,
就差这么一点
and I am this close to getting it.
我就需要再问...
I just need a couple of more...
拜托，我们还是做好自己工作吧
Let's just stick to what we're good at.
快点我们出发了
Let's stick to what we're good at. We're good at it.
倒计时五、四...
In five, four...
嗨，观众朋友大家好， 我是来自第6频道的爱普莉尔·奥尼尔
Hi, guys, this is April O'Neil from Channel 6 News
今天的纽约很美，同时，
and I am here in beautiful New York City
今天也是开春的第一天
on the first day of spring.
你们懂的
And you know what that means.
是时候把冬天的肉肉甩掉啦
It is time to shed that pesky winter weight.
今天我们有幸请到了
And here with me today
著名健身教练哈里帕斯纳克 你好，哈里
is celebrity fitness trainer Harley Pasternak. Hi, Harley.
早上好，爱普莉尔
Good morning, April.
我花了二十年的时间去研究动物
Twenty years I've studied the animal kingdom.
猪有肥的，牛也有肥的
There are fat pigs, there are fat cows.
但是从来没有肥胖的鸟
There are no fat birds.
好的，我希望你们去想象一只性感的海鸥
All right, I want you to visualize a sexy seagull.
让我们蹲下，然后展开翅膀
So we're going to squat down and flap your wings.
就这样，全身伸展
Right over there. Full extension.
想象你就要离开寒冷的北方
Picture you're leaving the cold north
你在飞翔，你在迁徙
and you're flying. You're migrating.
我上了四年的新闻专业， 现在就只能做这个
Four years of journalism school so that I can do that.
四年的大好青春，弗恩
Four years of my life, Vern.
实在是太无奈了
It's embarrassing.
听着，奥尼尔，我明白
Look, O'Neil, I get it,
你想要成为有专题新闻的大记者
you want to be a serious journalist.
我看你偷偷摸摸的在新闻房旁边走来走去
I see you sniffing around the newsroom
想寻找一些大新闻
for the big stories.
但是现在这样给予人们一些轻松的
But it's also okay to just give people something
像一些...一些泡沫一样的消息也是不错的
a little lighter. A little... Little froth.
- 泡沫？ - 你想本来
Froth? You know, how,
当你拿到一杯咖啡的时候，就像咖啡
when you get a coffee, it's just, like, coffee,
然后他们打一些泡沫在上面，， 那喝起来就...
then they put a little froth on it. It's kind of nice.
弗恩，那是奶泡
Vern, that's foam.
是啊，奶泡，泡沫，反正就是这个意思
Yes, foam, froth, you get the point.
它就是...就是很不错，很好喝，就像糖果一样
It's just... It's nice, it tastes good, it's candy.
俗话说
You ever heard the expression,
“不要和孩子抢糖吃”
"Never take candy from a baby"?
那是因为就连他们都喜欢糖果！
It's because even babies love candy!
你给予人们这种美好的事物
It's nice. And you're giving people
这个行为本来就很美好
something they like that's good and nice.
他们看着你，然后说
They look at you and they see,
“哇，那有一个很好的...那是
"Wow, there's a nice... There's...
糖果，重点是，我觉得
"...candy." The point is, I think that
你应该得到应有的奖励， 别太逼自己好吗？
you should be rewarded, not punishing yourself. Okay?
其实我...我已经准备好奖励你了
And I'm... I'm prepared to reward you.
我说我们去我哥们儿在市中心开的老饭馆吧
I say that we go to my buddy's old restaurant downtown.
那里感觉不错...
It's very vibey...
我们来的路上刚刚吃过了啊
We just ate on the way over here.
不是，我知道我们刚...我不是说
No, I know we just... I'm not saying
去吃个全餐，就是去吃点开胃菜
for a full meal, we're just gonna eat appeteasers.
我得去继续我的采访啦
I got to go finish that interview.
我们办公室见，弗恩!
I'll see you at the office, Vern!
我会在办公室等你!
I will see you at the office!
我只是想再追问一下，瑞瓦迪先生。
I just wanted to follow up, Mr. Rivetti.
你不是在玩我？ 你是怎么知道我的号码的？
Are you kidding me? How did you get my number?
- 如果我能再问一个问题 - 我已经把所有我知道的都说了 - 等等
Listen, I already told you everything I know about this crime, everything.
这样吧，你还想打探什么的话
Okay, you wanna know anything else,
回到码头那边
you go back down to the docks and you see
找我的手下史丹， 他会告诉你
my guy Stan. He'll tell you
所有你需要知道的事情，可以了吧？
anything else you need to know, okay?
还有请高抬贵手
And hey, do me a favor.
把我的号码删了，好吗？
Lose my number, all right?
找到了,这很明显。让我们打开它。
Good. It's clear. Let's open it up.
了解，我们把它打开搬出去
Container's good. Move on to the next one.
快点，马上把那些搬上卡车！
Move it out! Get those to the trucks now!
- 抬出去了 - 下个点！ 快点。
Move out, next point! Go, go, go.
- 第6频道   - 克里斯
Channel 6. Chris.
我是爱普莉尔，我正在码头这
Chris, it's April. I'm at the docks.
- 我们正在晚间报导当中，不管你有什么消息都要等着 - 不，不，我需要...
Whatever you got can wait for tomorrow. No, no, I need...
二，三，二，好了！
2-3-2, clear!
- 别挡着我的路 - 是的
- Get it out of my way. - Copy that.
可恶
Damn it.
第二单元，第三区，行动!
Unit two, area three, move!
动作快点！
I've got movement!
盯着这里！
Keep your eyes over here!
准备武器！
Weapons free!
守住！
Hold position!
撤退！快撤退！
Retreat! Retreat!
快离开这里！
Get out of here!
泰勒 泰勒！
Taylor. Taylor!
嗨，我正在和老妈通过SKYPE视频聊天呢
Hey. I'm Skyping with my mom.
你不会相信我刚才看到了什么
You have no idea what I just went through.
我吓坏了， 我看到了脚帮的一次行动
I am freaking out. I saw a Foot Clan attack.
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
我正在码头边上骑着脚踏车
I was riding my bike by the docks.
晚上很黑，
It was night, it's dark already
码头到处都是脚帮的士兵
and there are Foot Clan soldiers everywhere.
接着也不到哪里出来了一个家伙
Then out of nowhere, there was this guy
攻击脚帮的人
fighting back against them.
然后他还留下了一个符号
And he... He left behind this symbol.
我之前绝对见过
And I know that I've seen it before.
只是忘了在哪见过
I can't remember where.
那里绝对有一个人在
But there is someone fighting back
对抗脚帮
against the Foot Clan.
应该是存在一个这个城市的守护者
There is a vigilante in this city.
除了我之外没人知道
And no one knows, but I do.
既然我知道了， 我就终于有自己的新闻了
I know. And now I have my story.
再也不是那些泡沫跟奶泡的无聊杂事了
There is no more froth and foam for me.
你在说什么？
What?
没事忘了吧
Never mind.
听好了，我们需要今晚报导的消息， 有谁有好点子吗？
All right, we need a lead for tonight. Who's got it?
对于曼哈顿商业区
"Major redevelopments proposed
- 的建设新主张？ - 不行
"for lower Manhattan." No.
我这里有一个： 纽约警局因有效打击
I got something. "NYPD task force taking credit
脚帮活动而受到褒奖
"for small decline in Foot-related crime."
- 我喜欢这个，我们就用这个吧 - 好的, 头儿
I like that. Let's run with that. Yes, ma'am.
7点播出
7:00 AM broadcast,
我们有三分钟时间准备
we have three minutes to air.
奥尼尔，我们下次再说吧
Oh, O'Neil. I'll talk to you in a minute.
没事，我知道
I know that I'm actually overstepping
其实估计一会我身边就会围满了人
my boundaries by being here,
所以你最好
but I think that you're gonna
你最好能留在这边，听听我要说的话
I actually think that you're all gonna want to hear what I have to say.
我昨晚目击了一起
Um, I witnessed
在布鲁克林码头
an attempted Foot Clan robbery
预谋的脚帮劫案
at the docks in Brooklyn last night.
等等，监视器的确有记录到枪声
Hold on, the scanner said that gunshots were heard,
但是没有证据表示有脚帮的活动痕迹
but there were no reports of any Foot Clan activity.
那是因为不管他们原计画是什么
That's because whatever they were
他们都被人阻止了
attempting to do was stopped.
你在布鲁克林做什么？
What were you doing in Brooklyn anyway?
那天那边有什么夜市集会？
Was there a trampoline convention?
我之所以去布鲁克林
I was in Brooklyn because I was reporting,
是因为我不想坐在办公室无所事事
not sitting behind my desk, McNaughton.
好了，孩子们！
Okay, kids!
是谁阻止了脚帮？
Who stopped it?
有个...
Well, there was this guy.
我没能看得非常清楚的人。。。 但他移动迅速
I didn't see him clearly, but he was swinging
他用货柜箱
these giant shipping containers
把脚帮的士兵们都敲到了河里去
and knocking these guys into the... Into the river.
一定有个隐密的守护者在对抗着脚帮
There is a vigilante that is fighting back
这里面绝对包含大新闻
against the Foot Clan. There's a huge story here!
奥尼尔， 我想你一定是看到了超人，太酷了
O'Neil, I think you found Superman. That's cool.
这个守护者是真实存在的， 我亲眼看到了
The vigilante is real. I saw him.
奥尼尔，我假设你不会只是上来
O'Neil, I'm gonna assume
跟我们说这个天方夜谭的故事
that you would not come up here and tell us
你总得有点什么证据来证明吧
this fantastic story without some tangible proof.
我只拍到这张照片， 这个记号是画在一个货柜箱上的
I took this photo of one of the shipping containers.
事实上我觉得这是他故意留给我们的
I actually think that it may be his calling card.
这根本不算什么阿，奥尼尔， 这什么都不是！
This is nothing, O'Neil. This is nothing!
我想说的就是这个，有人
That's exactly the point. Somebody
阻止了脚帮的抢劫
stopped a Foot robbery and left no evidence.
并没有留下任何证据
There is nothing.
哦，我懂了
Oh, I get it.
你想让我在晚间新闻里
You wanted me to put "nothing"
- 就什么都不说 - 当然不是
on the nightly news. Of course not.
好了，我会假装我们没有过这一段对话的
You know, I'm gonna pretend we never had this conversation.
我现在就把她从我的脑子里删除
I'm erasing it from my mind.
剩下的人都回去工作吧
And the rest of us, we're gonna go back to work.
好了 干正事吧
Let's hit it!
观众朋友大家好， 欢迎收看第6频道早间新闻
Hello, everybody. Welcome to the Channel 6 Morning News.
关于新的防护法案
New developments in that ongoing sanitation strike
有了更多进展
to tell you about.
但是首先， 在和警局局长审视了
But first, after reviewing the city's
城市的犯罪情况之后
soaring crime rates with the police commissioner,
参议院丹莱格在市政厅门外， 步出了市政厅的大门
Councilman Dan Gregor took to the steps of City Hall,
重申了政府
reaffirming the city's commitment
对于打击犯罪集团
to fight against the rising crime organization
脚帮的决心和承诺
calling themselves the Foot Clan.
通过与萨克斯先生和
He did so on the heels of a renewed
萨克斯集团的合作来巩固这一承诺
contract with Eric Sacks and Sacks Industries.
利用萨克斯集团的研发和安保技术
Using the Sacks research and securities technology,
这座城市拥有了更多的把握
this city greatly improves its chances
将脚帮绳之于法
of bringing the Foot Clan to justice!
开始
你的人都是弱者
任务失败, 并不令我惊讶
我们在码头被那个守护者袭击了
We couldn't have anticipated the vigilante
许瑞德先生
showing up at the docks, Master Shredder.
你连这种小事都没办法处理
我们从来没见过这样的敌人
But we've never seen an enemy like this.
他们的大小
Their size.
他们的力量
Their strength.
他们绝不是人类
They're not human.
我从来不相信什么神话故事
I don't believe in fairy tales.
这也就是为什么社会想要消灭脚帮的原因
It's what society wants to reduce the Foot Clan to.
我们是一段神话
A myth.
脚帮会
But the Foot Clan
重新崛起的
will rise again.
把守护者给我抓住
Capture the vigilantes however you can.
去用无辜的市民当作诱饵
Use innocent people as bait.
绝对没有人能够阻挡我们
No one will stop us in our quest
重夺胜利的道路
to reclaim victory.
我们将要掌控这座城市
We will own this city.
女士先生们
Ladies and gentlemen, please join me
请和我一起欢迎纽约警局的首要赞助人
in welcoming the NYPD's top benefactor,
艾瑞克?萨克斯
Eric Sacks.
过奖了，过奖了
Please, please. Please.
请坐下，请坐下
Sit down, sit down.
我必须得说
I have to say,
今晚能够在这里看到这么多人， 实在是太美妙了
it's wonderful to see so many people out here tonight,
尤其是在这样一座
especially in a neighborhood
脚帮犯罪猖獗的城市里
so hard hit by the Foot's crime wave.
多年以前， 我的生活也因为悲剧而改变
Years ago, my life was touched by tragedy.
那时我是在世界顶尖的
I was a young scientist
科学团队工作的年轻科学家
working with a world-class team
进行绝对创新的研究上
on cutting-edge research.
但是我们的实验室被攻击了
And our laboratory was attacked,
资料被销毁器材被烧光
set fire to, robbed,
就是被脚帮的那群懦夫
by the cowards that call themselves the Foot Clan.
一些我的受雇人员
Several of my employees
在那一天牺牲了生命
lost their lives that day.
他们死的光荣， 会被我们所铭记
And it is in their honor, in their memory,
萨克斯集团， 旗下萨克斯生技
that Sacks Industries, whether through Sacks Biomed,
机械和建筑公司
Sacks Robotics or Sacks Construction,
将继续履行承诺，永远守护纽约
to keeping the city of New York, our city,
保护我们的城市安全宁静
safe.
所以不论是谁， 想要将罪恶之火烧到这座城市
So whenever someone takes flame to this city,
我就会出现在那，给予他正义的制裁
I will be there to put the fire out.
这是我的承诺
And that's a promise.
谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
萨克斯先生， 我是爱普莉尔?奥尼尔
Great work, sir. Very inspirational.
我父亲曾经和你共事过
Mr. Sacks. April O'Neil. You worked with my father.
哦！
Oh!
我完全无法相信，我自从...
I can't believe it. I haven't seen you since...
自从他的葬礼就没见过我
Since his funeral.
那已经是很久以前了
It was a long time ago.
是的
Yeah.
只是想要告诉你
I just wanted to tell you that your words
你的演讲让我很有共鸣
really resonated with me, and I hope to one day
我希望有一天也能够对这个城市
contribute to the city in the way that you do.
做出有如你这样的贡献
Well, it looks like you're doing a pretty good job.
好吧
Channel 6, very impressive, April.
这位记者你的抱负不错， 我完全受宠若惊
Um... Thank you. It's, uh...
谢谢，确实很多事情都事与愿委
It isn't exactly everything I anticipated it would be.
只要你能够保持真我
As long as you are true to yourself,
你的父亲都会为你感到骄傲的
your father will always be proud of you.
- 萨克斯先生， 你得在7点抵达市郊地区
Mr. Sacks, we have to be uptown at 7:00.
我们有机会再见
I'll see you on TV.
艾瑞克?萨克斯的话实在是太鼓舞人心了
Eric Sacks was so inspiring.
我知道这才是那些具有价值的新闻
I know this is a story that actually matters.
就像你那个超级英雄报导？
The superhero one?
好吧好主意，我们就跟踪报导吧
That's a good idea. I should chase that down.
大家怎么都在跑？
Where's everybody going?
- 奥尼尔! 你去哪??? - 嗨
- O'Neil! Where are you going? - Hey.
- 等一下 爱普莉尔！ - 嗨
April! Hey!
你是从哪边跑出来的? 请等等
What are you running from? Wait, wait!
监视器拍到大量脚足家族活动
Shots fired, Broadway and Centre Street.
他们挟持了人质，兄弟
Heavy Foot Clan activity at the Broad Street platform.
你知道我们不应该暴露在公众视线底下
But you know we're not supposed to go above ground.
我们之前已经破戒了， 就让事情有始有终吧
We started something, we gotta finish it.
这实在是太疯狂了
This is insane.
那只猫竟然在用筷子玩钢琴！
That cat is playing  Chopsticks with chopsticks!
别在天兵了
Don't be an idiot.
- 喔 - 好了
- Aw. - Okay.
我们出发吧，伙计们！
Let's rock 'n' roll, boys!
跑快点！
Run!
快逃！
Get out!
快走，快走！
Go, go!
如果你不想死
If you want to live, do it! Go on!
继续往下走
Just stay down!
到底下这里！
Get over here!
继续走！
Keep moving!
趴在地上！
Keep your hands where I can see them!
移动到这边
Move to the side.
- 是炸弹 - 闭嘴！
- They're bombs. - Shut up!
那边的！
On the ground!
所有人不许动！
Nobody move!
我们知道你们就在附近
We know you're out there!
如果你们不投降， 我们就开始处决人质
If you don't surrender, we start executing hostages!
把头低下！
Get your head down! Don't move!
让我再告诉你一遍 你这个懦夫！
Don't make me tell you again! Not a word!
怎样，别这样看着我！
Don't look at me!
别这样！ 别这样做！
Don't! Don't do it!
你！
You!
给我站起来！
Stand up!
他们来了！
All aboard!
我们上去!
On your 12!
移动！
Come on!
做的好
That's right.
Like a shadow, bra.
我们上去，移动！
Let's go! Let's move!
- 你看到那是什么了吗? - 他们从这里爬上去了
Right here. Some kind of freak!
感觉像是什么生物！
There were a couple of them!
就在上面
Whoo! Right past me!
就在上面, 天哪
They saved us.
快进去，进去，进去!
Go, go, go!
站住！ 别动！
Let's go, guys! Both sides!
是的，就是我说的！
Yeah, that's what I'm talking about!
Yeah, boys, bring it in.
令人难以置信的！
That was amazing. You were incredible!
漂亮的肘击，多尼
Great elbow, Donnie.
没错！ 那就是我说的
Oh, yeah! That's what I'm talking about.
这是我们的城市！ 这些是我们的街道！
This is our city! These are our streets!
这样就对了嘛
You mess with us, you step into
the Wu, whoo, Tang!
是的！ 你有见到那个人吗
Ooh, yeah! Did you see that guy's
就像在树林中潜行
jaw connect with the concrete?
你看到我刚才在火车之间穿梭了吗！
He'll be drinking out of a sippy cup for months!
我就是说这个，兄弟
Ah, that's what I'm talking about, brothers.
我就像是暗夜中的黑影，来去无踪
Like shadows in the night. Completely unseen.
- 那是什么? - 是相机的闪光... - 我们知道那是快门声
It's a camera flash.
是谁拍的照片？
Who's behind the camera flash?
根据我的推测是一个女的
By my calculations, it's a girl.
- 我们要杀了她吗 - 你说什么？ -我们可以温柔地杀
Give her some flowers, earn her trust.
- 你不能滥用你的力量，这件事我来搞定 - 别，别，到这来
I got this. Raph, no, no, no! Come on!
- 把相机给我
Give me the camera.
- 你们看...他又在学蝙蝠侠讲话了
Ooh, look, he's doing his Batman voice.
他长得实在太火辣了， 我感觉我的壳都硬起来了
She's so hot, I can feel my shell tightening.
我们能听得到你淫荡的心声
We can hear you!
如果你不把相机给我， 我就会...
If you don't give me the camera, I'm gonna...
够了！
Enough!
- 拉斐尔，别多嘴 - 靠 ...
Back off, Raph.
我好不容易能当一次蝙蝠侠
I only saw Batman once!
女士你好，我诚挚向你道歉
Ma'am, hello. I apologize.
我的兄弟刚才忘记对你稍微客气一点了
My colleague here forgot to say "please."
所以
So,
现在可以请你把相机给我们吗？
would you please hand over the camera?
不要怕...不要怕
No, no, no, no. Whoa.
放心，没事的，这只是面具
Whoa. Chill. It's just a mask. See? Don't freak out.
看吧
Right?
啊！
Ah!
我觉得你这招的确是奏效了
Oh, I think that went well.
呼吸定态，血压稳定
Breathing steady. Blood pressure stabilizing.
- 情况稳定 - 爱因斯坦又在演医生了
Why are we still here playing doctor?
他好不容易有这机会
She may have a head injury.
恭喜你阿，这次的病人还是个女神
Uh, correction. She's a hot chick
唤醒他是保护
who may have a head injury, which makes it
- 城市的责任 - 女士? 女士?
- our civic duty to... - Ma'am, ma'am.
你能听见我说话吗？ 知道你在哪座城市吗？
Can you hear me? Do you know what city you're in?
你知道你在哪里吗？
Do you know where you are?
你曾经看过那个一只小猫
Have you seen that video where the cat
用筷子玩钢琴的视频吗？
plays  Chopsticks with the chopsticks?
你能别在这边捣乱吗？
Can we focus here?
伙计们, 别这样， 给他留点空间
Guys, please! Come on. Give her some air.
你们到底是什么？
What are you?
好吧，小姐
Well, Miss,
我们是忍者
uh, we're ninjas.
也是变种人
We're mutants.
基本上我们就是乌龟
Well, technically, we're turtles.
而且是青少年！
Oh, and we're teenagers!
但你要聊成人话题也是可以啦
But we can still have adult conversations.
等等，这是...
Wait, wait, wait. So...
所以你们是...
You're...
忍者，变种，
Ninja, mutant,
乌龟，青少年？
turtle, teenagers?
你这样讲听起来很搞笑耶
Well, when you put it like that, it sounds ridiculous!
你看吧， 他看我们就跟看怪胎一样
See, she's looking at us like we're freaks.
我猜这就是你要拍我们的原因对吧？
I bet that's why you took our picture, wasn't it?
可以展示给你的朋友们看？
To show your friends?
这是件好事！ 也许他还认识其他女神
Bro, that's a good thing! Maybe she has hot friends.
- 你在找这个吗？ - 别摔坏它
Looking for this? Don't break it.
不不不不，请不要
No, no, no. Please.
我要跟你说多少次？
How many times do I have to tell you?
我们不破坏东西， 我们只会摆平它们
We don't break things, we fix them.
多尼的话早就把这手机格式化了
Donnie already wiped the phone, genius.
问题就解决了，你这蠢蛋
Problem solved, moving on.
谁知道呢 他没让你在这发号施令
And who put you in charge? You know who did.
- 你怎么知道他不会 - 喔 好紧张的气氛阿
Ooh, tension! It's been like 30 whole minutes
你们在这边吵吵闹闹都半小时了
since you guys had this argument.
李奥纳多
Leonardo, if we want to make it home before Master,
差不多该结束这场争执了吧
we gotta hustle.
李奥纳多？
Leonardo?
别把你看到的说出去
Do not say a word about this to anyone.
如果你走漏了？ 我们会来找你
If you do, we will find you.
爱普莉尔?奥尼尔
April O'Neil.
我们回去了，拉斐尔
We're on the move, Raphael.
拉斐尔？
Raphael?
是啊！
Yeah!
我们会来找你，奥尼尔
We'll find you, O'Neil.
拍谢
I'm sorry, that came across
我说的感觉好像一个怪叔叔
super creepy, okay?
但我们会来找你的
We will find you, though.
- 耶！ - 真是棒阿，伙计！
I was on fire, bro!
你们知道吗？
Did you see me back there?
他可以排我心目中的女神前两位！
Guys, I totally talked to a girl!
闭嘴，米奇！
Shut up, Mikey!
耶，哥们！
Yeah, bra!
米奇，刚才你放屁吧？
Mikey, was that you?
呵呵被发现了
Pepperoni.
李奥纳多... 我就知道是这样
Leonardo. I know those names. I know those names.
拉斐尔，李奥纳多...
Raphael, Raphael. Leonardo.
晚上好
Good evening.
我是爱普莉尔·奥尼尔
This is April O'Neil,
正在我爸爸的实验室里录影
reporting live from my daddy's lab.
我知道这听起来可能很无聊
I know it sounds pretty boring,
但实际上他做的东西非常酷
but actually, he does some pretty cool stuff.
把录影机关了，爱普莉尔
Time to put the camera away, April.
喔不，爸爸！
Aw, Dad!
你们好，我将给你们展示...
And now I will show you
非常奇妙的东西
something amazing.
这是从另一个宇宙星球
It's supposed to be from a different planet
得来的电视
in outer space! Here we go.
啊！
Ah!
萨克斯先生
Mr. Sacks,
你现在正在进行的是什么实验呢？
what sort of experiments are you doing here?
这真是很难回答的问题
Oh, that's a very complicated question.
我们正在企图改变世界
We're trying to change the world.
来看着镜头
Look at the camera!
你好，史林特
Hello, Splinter.
而这些是我的小乌龟们， 这是李奥纳多
And these are my little turtles, Leonardo,
拉斐尔，
Raphael,
米开朗基罗，以及多纳太罗
Michelangelo and Donatello.
我们来看看你
The fans want to see you!
我就知道是这样
I knew it.
那些守护者，我看到他们了 我看到他们了
The vigilante, I saw him. I saw them! I saw them.
我认识他们， 当我还是小女孩的时候
I've known them since I was a little girl.
他们都是我的宠物
They were my pets.
他们是我儿时的宠物，
They were my childhood pets,
还都是以文艺复兴时期 知名艺术家的名字命名的
and they were named after Italian Renaissance painters.
天啊，我还是回房间里面吧
Mom, I want to move back home.
他在这里吗？
Is he here?
我没看到他的影子
I don't see him.
多尼？
Donnie?
等着，根据我的计算有74%的成功率
My thermal scans indicate there's a 74% variable
但是同时有61%的概率是他在躲猫猫
that there's a 61% chance he's not...
他不在这里
That he's not here, guys.
没事没事，他不在这里
That he's not here.
好了，跟着我
Okay.
我们...偷偷...溜进去
Fall in, quietly.
嘘
Dude.
兄弟们，我要把那个妹
So, guys, if it wasn't already obvious with that girl,
他是我的
dibs.
如果被史林特师父抓包
If Master Splinter catches us,
他一定会处罚我们
he'll send us back to the Ha'shi.
我才不要被处罚
I ain't going back to the Ha'shi.
每次还不都是因为你
Every time we're in the Ha'shi, it's because of you.
你们不用再担心
Well, bro, you won't have to worry about me
我会拖你们下水
dragging you down anymore.
你这话是什么意思？
What's that supposed to mean?
有机会我会搬出去住
I'm going out on my own. First chance I get.
这样我们的嘻哈圣诞专辑怎么办？
How are we gonna finish our hip-hop Christmas album, bro?
你是负责炒热气氛的耶！
You're the hype man!
- 闭嘴啦 - 你才闭嘴 - 闭嘴
Shut up.
- 安静 - 安静
- 有口水喷到我的眼睛了
I got glop in my eye.
他哪都不会去的， 我们到哪都不分开的
Shh! He's not going anywhere. We all stick together.
对不起刚口水喷到你
Sorry I spit in your eye, bro.
兄弟们...
Shh! Guys? Guys.
我们有麻烦了...
We got a bogey.
呃...
Uh...
你们去哪了？
Where have you been?
我们一直都在...
We weren't...
我有东西忘了拿了！
I forgot to soak my retainer!
你看
I'm totally sleepwalking!
米奇正在梦游，正在离开！
Look, Mikey's sleeping and walking.
他可是完全无辜的啊
He's totally innocent.
够了！ 你们违反不能任意在人前出现的规定
Enough! You disobeyed a direct order.
发生什么事了？
Why did you go above ground? What happened?
非常好
Very well.
如果这就是你们所以期望发生的事情
If that's how it's going to be,
通通进去！
to the Ha'shi!
奥尼尔，什么事情需要叫我到这来？
O'Neil! All right, what was so important I had to get here?
- 好的，你准备好了吗? - 是的 随时
Okay. Are you ready? Yeah.
好的
Okay. You know how
- 你知道我之前说过守护者的故事 - 是的
I saw the vigilante? Yeah.
只是当时我没有任何照片证据
But I had no photos or evidence to show you,
所以听起来很疯狂
so I just sounded crazy.
- 是的 - 这一次我又见到他们了
Yes. Okay. But I saw him again.
我之所以说"他们"
Well, I didn't see him again,
是因为总共有4个
I saw them, because there's four.
不是一个，是4个， 我需要你把这
There's not just one, there's four. And I was standing
做为我的独家新闻
as close to them as you are to me right now.
他们长什么样？
What'd they look like?
我现在可以告诉你
I'll show you.
什么？
What?
就是这个
Like this.
像乌龟？
Like turtles?
不是看起来像乌龟
Well, they don't look like turtles
因为他们就是乌龟
because they are turtles.
每个都有身高一米八还会说话
They're over six feet tall and they speak English.
天阿
Oh, my God.
我熬了一整夜，等等，我都通宵了
I was awake all night, please look, I was awake all night
过去三个月犯罪新闻
googling all of the thwarted crimes
所有类似乌龟迹象活动的
over the past three months, and this symbol
这个符号出现在每一个犯罪现场
appeared at every single one.
你看！ 每一个都有
Look! Every single one of them.
看这， 在这里，在这里，在这里，在这里，在这里
This one, look. Here, here, here, here, here.
这是日本古代的符号， 象征着家庭
And it's an ancient Japanese symbol that means "family."
等等，我的电脑呢
Wait, it's on my laptop.
我的天 我不相信这就是真相！
I can't believe you brought me in to do this!
对在这，就在这
It's here, it's here.
这是我爸以前的实验室
This is my father's lab.
这是相同的实验室
This is the same lab
那只老鼠跟这些乌龟
where these things were born
就是在这出现的...
or created or mutated.
变种...
Or, I don't know the terminology,
你可以认真听我说吗?
but will you please just look at what
这些都能连起来
I'm showing you and listen to me. It's all connected.
这些乌龟就是守护者
The turtles are the vigilantes
守护者也就是这些乌龟
and the vigilantes are these turtles.
你看，这是香肠起司披萨
Pizza has cheese,
你要快点吃阿，你要补充营养的
tomato sauce, all your favorite stuff.
它们不吃这个的
Eat it. You guys need nutrition. Or not.
我来整理一下
I just want to be clear.
你现在就是想跟我说， 现在有...
You are now telling me that there are
4个一米八高的乌龟还会说话
four six-foot talking turtles walking around New York City,
在纽约走来走去， 其他人都没看到就只有你遇到了？
and no one has seen them but you?
没错! 这就是我要说的
That's what I'm telling you.
我不是故意要笑
I don't mean to laugh,
我们还需要知道什么？
but is there anything else we should know about them?
他们都是忍者
They're ninjas.
你说什么？
I'm sorry, what?
他们也是忍者
And they do karate.
OK，你可以滚了
Okay, get out.
奥尼尔！
O'Neil!
这不算是最糟的
It could have been worse.
我刚被炒鱿鱼，还有什么更糟的？
I just got fired, Vern. How could it be worse?
这不一定是坏事， 你可以利用这段时间好好
Maybe it's good. Maybe you should take a little time,
照顾下自己
take care of yourself.
来吧，我送你一程
Come on, let me give you a ride.
除非你能带我去萨克斯公司
Not unless you're going to the Eric Sacks estate.
我不做其他无聊的报导
April... Hey! I'm not giving up on this story.
你得放下手
You gotta put that to bed.
你曾经认识的那些着名报导人员
Would all of those other great reporters
他们会放弃吗?
that you worked with, would they have "put it to bed"?
那不一样
No. That's different.
那怎么不一样了？
How is it different?
他们都是从我这样的困境里出来的， 对吧?？
They all started exactly where I am, right?
我只好开着第6频道的新闻车，
I'm not driving the Channel 6 news van
送你去萨克斯公司了
onto the Sacks estate.
- 谁让你这么做的? - 是你阿
Who asked you to do that? Uh, you did.
如果你能说声谢谢那就更好了
And a "thanks" would have been nice.
或许哪天你才是那个应该感谢我的人
Maybe one day you're gonna be thanking me.
你去找艾瑞克?萨克斯想做什么？
So, what do you want with Eric Sacks?
我爸爸曾经为他工作
My dad used to work for him.
他是唯一一个可以证明我
He's the only person that's gonna be able
到底是不是疯了的人
to tell me whether or not I'm crazy.
为什么疯了？
Crazy about what?
我才不想让你笑我
I don't need you to laugh at me also.
说吧，奥尼尔
Oh, come on, O'Neil.
这是最后一次采访了
This is the Fenwick Express, it's a
在这里我们一视同仁， 一个非常安全的环境
judgment-free zone. A cocoon of safety.
你保证？
Promise?
我希望这是值得你去作
I'm insulted that you would suggest otherwise.
你们处罚经过11小时了
Ooh, 11 hours in the Ha'shi.
你们打算对于昨晚发生的
Are you sure none of you want to tell me
事情一个字都不说吗？
where you were last night?
你在三轮车上怎么样？
How you holding up, fellas?
啊！ 我不会摔下的不会的
Ah! I ain't breaking if Donnie ain't breaking.
他是不会摔下的
Experiencing intense nausea but not breaking.
伙伴们？ 我现在已经找到平衡点了！
Guys? I'm in the zone!
不过我快脑充血了！
There is literally nothing that could break me right now!
披萨来了
Starting to break.
你们肯定都吃过五味起司披萨
Of course, you've all tasted the five-cheese pizza.
但是我这盒 ...
But this,
是所有起司商人
cheesemongers have speculated
花了数百年都无法确认的珍宝
of its existence for centuries.
集合了众多高人尽情烹制
Da Vinci's original masterpiece.
我来向你们展示 ...
I submit to you...
有99种起司的披萨
...the 99-cheese pizza.
哦！
Oh!
这是不可能的
It's not possible.
米奇，这是个陷阱！
Mikey, it's a trap! A pizza with that variety
一个披萨能放那么多种起司绝对不合理的！
of cheese is a culinary impossibility!
你要我举例一下里面的起司成分吗
Shall I list the ingredients? No.
切达起司
Cheddar...
- 波萝伏洛起司 - 米奇，你别去看它！
Provolone... Mikey, don't you do it!
大概你不知道的起司
Asiago...
一起保存它！
Keep it together!
塔莱焦起司
Taleggio...
- 要坚持住阿! 千万要忍住阿 - 我根本都没听过这种披萨
I don't even know what that is.
当然肯定有莫扎里拉起司
Mozzarella, of course.
好，好！我们离开
All right, all right, all right! We left the lair
是因为脚帮绑架人质
because the Foot were taking hostages
我们去狠狠教训他们
and we kicked some serious butt,
但是被一个
and there was this girl named April O'Neil
叫做奥尼尔的女孩拍到照片
who took our picture,
但是我们已经把事情摆平了
but we took care of it.
你这蠢货
Idiot.
不，我最坏的设想成真了
Oh, no, my worst fears have been realized.
别担心了，没什么事的！
Don't worry about it. Donnie erased the picture!
我们又不会有什么危险
We're not in danger.
不，现在有危险的是 爱普莉尔?奥尼尔！
No. It's April O'Neil who is in danger!
把那个女孩找到，把他带到这里来
Find the girl. Bring her here.
但是，师父，你说不去...
But,  sensei, you said to not go...
找到那个女孩！
Find the girl!
遵命，找到那个女孩
Find the girl.
这就是我告诉汤普森的故事， 然后他就把我开除了
That's what I told Thompson and she fired me.
所以他们是外星人？
So they're aliens?
这么说太蠢了
No, that's stupid.
他们是忍者
They're reptiles.
我想他们是在帮助市民
They help people, I guess.
是你把那些小动物养大
Heroes in the half-shell.
- 是阿 - 我觉得这也说不是很疯狂...
Okay. Come on. It's not that crazy.
动物的世界里...充满了...
I... The animal kingdom is full of...
譬如可以双脚站立走路的狗
I used to have a dog that could moonwalk.
谢谢你送我来
Thanks for the ride, Vern.
小事一桩
Yeah. No problem.
没有什么比
Nothing better than
把一个美女， 送到富商的家门口更闷了...
dropping off a pretty girl at a rich guy's house.
你好，我是爱普莉尔?奥尼尔 我来这见艾瑞克?萨克斯
Hi, it's April O'Neil, here to see Eric Sacks.
爱普莉尔，没想到那么快就看到你
April's arrived early this year.
很抱歉我突然来访，萨克斯先生
I'm sorry to barge in on you like this, Mr. Sacks.
没关系，别太过意不去
No, no, no. Please, please.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我正在做一个独家新闻
I've been working on a story.
关于对抗脚帮
And I have this theory that there are these vigilantes
的城市守护者
that are fighting back against the Foot.
我想你和我爸爸， 应该是曾经创造出他们的人
I think you and my father may have created them.
我...我不太确定你说的...
Uh, I'm not sure I...
请你务必告诉我， 关于那个研究的所有细节
Can you please tell me everything that you know
关于文艺复兴计画？
about Project Renaissance?
Hmm.
好吧...它...就是一个梦想
Well, um, it was a dream.
一场随你的父亲去世就破灭的梦想
A dream that died with your father.
如果它并没有灭亡呢？
What if it isn't dead?
那是不可能的
That's impossible.
那场大火中， 我们失去所有的研究资料
We lost all our research in the fire,
设备，所有东西，每件事物
all our specimens, everything.
我过去的15年之间
I've spent the last 15 years
都在试图重新复制当年的成果
trying to replicate the results.
那场大火你并没有失去所有
You didn't lose everything in the fire.
这不可能是真的
This can't be real.
这就是真的
It is real.
我看到了他们4个
I saw all four of them.
你真的想知道研究项目的事情吗？
Do you really want to know about Project Renaissance?
- 是的 - 跟我来
Yes. Come with me.
我出生在日本冲绳的军事基地
I was born in Japan, at a military base in Okinawa.
我父亲去了越南
My father went to Vietnam.
就再也没有回来
Didn't come back.
我在战争外就是一个局外人
I was an outsider in a foreign land.
我吓坏了
A freak.
我是一个绝望无助的小男孩
I was a powerless and helpless boy.
直到当地的师父收养我
Until a local  sensei took me under his wing.
是他救了我
And he saved me.
传授我课业， 也就是之后我与你父亲共享的知识
Taught me lessons that I later shared with your father.
日本，第9世纪时
Ninth-century Japan.
一个邪恶君主在全国各地
An evil warlord ruled the land.
水源里下毒， 带来了黑暗的年代
He poisoned the water supply, bringing on the dark ages.
死亡，疾病，民不聊生
Death and disease and suffering ran rampant.
就像脚帮
Not unlike the Foot Clan
这样残害城市
and what they'd like to do to our city.
直到有一天，英雄出现了
Then one day, a hero arose.
研发出能够治愈君主
A great alchemist discovered the antidote
下毒的疫苗
to the warlord's poison.
可是英雄不是天生的
The cure-all
而是被创造出来的
for his evil.
你的父亲和我正在尝试 重现万灵药
Your father and I were trying to recreate that cure-all.
我们研发了疫苗
We developed a mutagen
能够刺激的生物自我疗复
capable of stimulating self-repair
精细到个体细胞的层面上
on a cellular level.
你们打算拿那个做什么？
What were you going to do with it?
试想一下如果纽约
Imagine New York City,
被生化武器攻击
being victim to a chemical attack.
然而这种解药， 将会完全抵御这种攻击
This mutagen would be able to reverse its effects.
将会拯救城市，拯救人民
It would save the city, it would save the people.
这些实验物品，这些乌龟
Those test subjects, those turtles...
他们体内流动的是
Running in their blood
那次实验唯一留下来的成果了
is the last of this precious mutagen.
在你告诉我之前
And up until a few moments ago,
我还以为我们失败了
I thought we failed.
我以为他们都在那场大火中丧生了
I thought they died in the fire. How...
他们怎么可能活下来的？
How could they have lived?
因为是我救了他们
Because I saved them.
当然，你的确会去救
Of course you did.
爱普莉尔，这些基因隐藏了巨大的能量
April, the mutagen possesses powers
远远超过我们的想像
beyond our wildest hopes.
不论你需要什么资源
Whatever resources you need,
告诉我
I'm here.
让我们一起努力找到他们吧
Let's work together. We'll find them.
改写人类的历史， 就完全寄托在他们身上了
The course of human history may depend on it.
我想你会理解的
I'll show you out.
嘿！ 爱普莉尔！
Bam! You've been hacked!
我是多纳太罗
By Donatello. Remember me?
那只乌龟， 还记得我吧？听到我说话吗
Turtle. Four eyes. But enough about me.
我说过我们会找到你的
We told you we'd find you. Meet us here.
来这个地点，自己一个人来
And come alone. Or... Or else we're...
如果你不照做...你会被惩罚的
You shall be punished and stuff.
有人吗？
Hello?
是你们叫我来这边的
You told me to come here.
我自己一个人来的
I didn't bring anyone with me.
我完全按照你们的要求...
I did exactly...
好的！ 你就是 爱普莉尔?奥尼尔吗？
Okay! Are you April O'Neil?
启动视网膜扫描
Initiating retinal scan.
扫瞄，扫瞄 扫瞄，扫瞄
Scanning, scanning, scanning, scanning.
扫描完毕， 是她，确定是她
Scan complete. It's her. It's her. Guys, it's her!
当然是她，多尼
Of course it's her, Donnie.
嘿 你好阿 难以置信你真的自己来这了
Hey. Really glad you could make it.
我们今天要给你
Hey. There's someone important
介绍一个新的人认识， 但是首先...
we want to introduce you to, but first...
嘿 小妞，欢迎来到我的洞穴里
Aw, yeah, welcome to my crib, girl.
我们在哪里？
Where are we?
这该怎么说
Hey, it's our Fortress of Solitude.
在霍格华兹魔法学校
Our Hogwarts.
在X战警学校
Our Xavier Academy.
在星际战舰上！
State-of-the-art WonderDome!
我们...
Ugh.
该不会在下水道里吧？
Are we in the sewer?
不是的...
No.
- 你还是坦白一点吧 - 是的
- Technically, yes. - Yeah.
是的，是在下水道
Yeah, it's a sewer.
是你把我们带来这里的，爱普莉尔
You brought us here, April.
史林特？
Splinter?
你该不会把老爸名字
How does she know his name?
告诉她了吧？
Did you tell her his name?
她竟然知道
Maybe she's clairvoyant.
难道她是绝地武士！
Maybe she's a Jedi!
靠近点
Come closer.
好久不见了
It's been a long time.
嗯...
Mmm.
你眼睛长得和你爸爸一样
You always did have your father's eyes.
我无法理解
I don't understand.
别害怕， 所有事情你很快就都清楚了
Don't be afraid. All will be made clear.
这实在太疯狂了
This is crazy.
你到这里干嘛？
我的徒弟
最近发生了一个奇蹟
There's been a miracle.
那些给我们制造很多麻烦的守护者
The vigilantes who've been causing us so much trouble?
它们曾经是我的实验样品
They're the test subjects.
那些我们以为
Those itty-bitty box turtles
在大火中丧生的小乌龟
that we thought we lost in the fire?
它们还活着，许瑞德大师
They're alive, Master Shredder.
然后它们还长大了， 成为...
And they've grown into something
非常强大的生物...
powerful.
抓到他们当然不容易， 但是如果我们能抓住
It won't be easy to capture them, but if we can,
然后把多年以前的
we can finally carry out the plan
实验成果提取出来
that we had all those years ago.
族将会获得无限的权力和金钱
纽约将落入我们手中，许瑞德大师
The city will be ours.
奥尼尔是发现他们的人
O'Neil's daughter was the one who found them
她也是那个可以引领我们， 找到它们的人
and she will be the one who will take us right to them.
发现信号了
There's the ping.
我们破解了他们安全防护措施
We've breached the cloaking security.
听我说，爱普莉尔
Listen closely, April.
被带到实验室之前的事情
I don't remember a time
我都不记得了
before living in that laboratory.
那个命运之夜 就像其他普通夜晚一样开始了
That fateful night started like any other.
萨克斯给我们注射了药剂
Sacks gave us our injections.
你的父亲监控我们的生命体变化 >
Your father made sure our vital signs were strong.
以及你，和平时一样
And you, as always,
还是拿着那些食物在喂我们
provided us with a special treat.
当我的兄弟们都睡着之后
After the brothers went to sleep,
我听到很大的动静
I heard loud voices.
到处都是烟雾的气味
There was the smell of smoke.
警报的声响
Alarms sounded.
你的父亲发现了真相
Your father had discovered the truth
他为之工作的那人真相
behind the man he was working for.
于是他放火烧了实验室
He set fire to the lab.
他用尽最后的力气
His last breath was taken
想要摧毁许瑞德的计画
trying to destroy Shredder's plan.
我很害怕的时候
I was terrified.
但是你却出现了
But then, you appeared.
把我们都带到安全的地方
And ushered us to safety.
在此之后我都没有机会表达
I never had a voice then,
< 但是我现在要谢谢你  爱普莉尔
but I than
嗯
Mmm.
我们在下水道里游荡, 直到我们发现了这里
We wandered the sewers until I found this place.
当时那突变的物质
It was then that the mutagen
那些注射进我们血液的基因
that was injected into our blood
开始从各方面改变了我们
began to change us in miraculous ways.
我之前见证了你父亲是多么爱你
I saw how your father loved you
我知道我也要对这些乌龟 表示相同的爱护
and I knew I had to show that same love to the turtles.
于是我就变成父亲了
I became their father
他们成为了我的孩子
and they became my sons.
就像每个孩子, 他们受到外界文化的吸引
Like all children, they were drawn
我知道总有一天
to the distractions of popular culture.
他们想出去探索这个世界
They would want to explore the world above.
他们会被世人嘲笑
They would be ridiculed.
他们必须学习技能保护自己
They would need to learn to protect themselves,
包括精神上和肉体上
both mentally and physically.
嘿 你们有人想玩巴巴克吗？
Hey. Does anyone want to play Buck-Buck?
巴克 一！
Buck one!
巴克 二！
Buck two!
巴克 三！
Buck three!
你们在做什么阿？
Where you going, Raph?
- 别这样 - 来嘛, 跟着跳阿
Come on. I can't do it by myself.
我们需要四个一起！
I need all four!
愚蠢的游戏
You're a Buck short.
是的， 就像你 愚蠢米奇！
Yeah, that sounds stupid. Like you, Mikey!
兄弟们
That's why you're just the hype man, bra.
- 你有没有看到那些动作？ - 不要紧的
- See these moves? - Yeah, whatever, man.
忍者技艺
然后我发现了手册
And then I found a way.
首先我得自学成材
First, I would teach myself the ancient art of Ninjutsu.
Oh!
他们四个兄弟跟随我的教导
The brothers followed my lead,
以飞快的速度进步
accelerating at a wondrous rate!
我来无影去无踪
Wassup, bra? Want some of this?
就像个幽灵！
I'm like a ghost!
我在这，我在这，我就像个影子
I'm over here, now I'm over here, bra. Like a shadow!
我就是影子火龙！
I'm a flame shadow fire dragon!
他们的天赋也同时是
Ow!
他们活力的来源！
Their gift was also their passion.
他们在这样的艰苦训练中生活
They lived, breathed and dreamed
呼吸以及幻想
all things martial arts.
之后
Then,
他们终于准备好了
they were ready.
武士刀的刀刃闪亮如新
The katana, most noble of all the blades.
这是给与领导者的武器
It is the weapon of a leader.
所以他们热爱的事物
Everything they are,
以及所有他们想成为的事物
and everything that they've become
都被你当年所展现出来的勇气， 所拯救而成为现实
was made possible by the bravery that
在那个命运决定的夜晚
you displayed on that fateful night.
是的，兄弟
Dude.
我当时也就是小女孩
I was just a little girl.
是你给了我们自由
And you gave us freedom
如果换成别人， 可能就把我们关在笼子里了
where others would have kept us in cages.
等等，师父
Wait a minute, Dad.
这些年你一直跟我们说的是，那晚
All these years you told us we were rescued from the fire
是一个伟大的守护者之魂救我们的， 一个“守护者”
by a great guardian spirit, the  Hogo-sha.
现在在你们面前的
That's right.
就是守护者
And this is the  Hogo-sha.
什么？
What?
原来我的女朋友就是守护者阿
My girlfriend's totally the  Hogo-sha.
Ow.
我们有优秀的工程师
Fortunately, our engineers
重新打造
have been making great progress
你装甲里面的机械系统
in refining the robotics in your armor.
我们要让你装甲性能再度等级
We're taking it to the next level,
和古代的优良传统合而为一
bridging the gap between ancient tradition
无懈可击
and modern warfare.
今晚可以喝乌龟汤了
你为什么要带我来这？
Why did you bring me here?
想了解你把我们的存在告诉了谁
To find out who you told of our existence.
根本没人相信我 除了艾瑞克?萨克斯
Nobody that believed me, except for Eric Sacks.
萨克斯...
Sacks.
这就是我最担心的
Just as I feared.
萨克斯绝对不是我们的朋友
Sacks is not a friend.
他的灵魂已经被污染毒害了
His soul has been poisoned
受到了黑暗力量的影响
by the influence of a dark master.
许瑞德
The Shredder.
许瑞德在日本把萨克斯抚养长大
Shredder practically raised Sacks in Japan.
他对于萨克斯就是父亲的存在
He's like a father to him.
萨克斯为了他的师父，会做任何事情
Sacks will do anything for his master.
等等，等等
Wait, wait.
萨克斯和许瑞德？
Sacks and Shredder?
那我们为什么不去把他们杀掉？
So, why aren't we out there hunting them down?
拉斐尔
Because, Raphael,
因为许瑞德是非常厉害的勇士
The Shredder is a skilled warrior
他的残暴程度超乎你的想像！
whose cruelty is ever-reaching!
而你们还只是个孩子
And you are just teenagers.
在你们血液里的变种基因， 就是他们正在寻找的东西
The mutagen in your blood is of great value to them.
现在萨克斯
Now that Sacks has confirmation
已经确认你们的存在
that you are alive,
我很担心他们会带来战争
I fear they will bring the fight to us.
喔...不会吧...
Oh, no.
快点伙计们！
Stand by to make entry. Let's move!
快，快，快！
Go, go, go!
有入侵 有入侵！
Perimeter infringe. Breached! We have incoming!
有敌人进来了
Oh, no! Oh, no! We got two breaches.
我们有两处被突破了！
Fan room, weapons wall!
米奇，去右边武器室！ 你和多尼跟我来
Mikey, flank right! Donnie, on me!
该走了，快点！
We gotta go! Go, go!
所有人保持警戒
Stand by to set charge.
行动开始，我们开始突袭
Lock and load. We're going on 10.
没有生命迹象，继续搜索
No live ammo. Tranqs only.
要确保他们活着！
Take 'em alive!
不！ 快退回去！
No! Get back!
多尼！
Donnie!
Engage!
拿下他！
Get him!
快过来，过来
There they are! Neutralize them!
他们好像很适应黑暗的环境！
They've got tranq darts!
记得不要让他们打到你
Well, don't let them hit your skin.
我们走！ 动起来！
Let's go! Let's move!
那里！
Over there!
在12点方向
Tango at 12!
你们好阿，你们觉得可以搞定我？
Wassup, bra? Oh, you think you can handle this, huh?
我只要全力穿过去 看我"猛龟出闸"，蠢蛋！
I'm a snapping turtle, fool. Snap, snap, snap!
跟你们说过了吧，你们可以吗！
I meant to do that! I meant to do it!
我们需要去那边
We got a breach in the fan room!
拉飞尔！ 你去那边！
Raph! Get to the fan room!
别每次都跟我说我该怎么做？
Why are you always telling me what to do?
照做就对了！ 米奇，你得把爱普莉尔带走，快！
Just go! Mikey, you gotta get April out of here, now!
包在我身上！
I got this!
爱普莉尔，跟我来。
April, come with me.
我得把你稍微藏起来
I got a safe place for you to hide.
如果你渴了
And if you get thirsty,
我在冰箱后面藏着柳橙汁
I got a secret stash of Orange Crush behind the fridge.
记得不要告诉拉斐尔
Don't tell Raph.
许瑞德...
Shredder.
这么多年
All these years
我一直试图重制那些变种基因
I've been trying to recreate the mutagen.
而你...
And you?
你竟然把他们藏在地底下
You just handed it to me.
我不会让你对我的儿子们出手的
You will not lay a hand on my sons.
你的儿子们？
Your sons?
你还真觉得自己是他们的父亲？
You think you're their father?
很不错阿，小老鼠！
Very good, rat!
师父！
Sensei!
多尼！
Donnie!
奥尼尔！ 快来这里！
Hang on, Leo! Be right there!
你这个愚蠢的小女孩！
You stupid little girl!
爱普莉尔！
April!
师父！
Sensei!
别过来孩子，你退后！
No, my son, stay back!
师父！
Sensei!
师父！师父！
Sensei! Dad!
师父！ 你到底要做什么？
Dad! What are you... What are you doing?
快躲起来！
Hide!
不！
No!
快自己逃命吧！
Save yourselves!
乌龟们，放下武器
Children, drop your weapons,
或你的父亲将会死
or your father will die.
不！
No!
第四个去哪了？
Where's the fourth?
他已经死了
He's dead.
毁了这个地方
Destroy this place.
保持前进！
Keep moving!
- 别, 不, 不 - 别推我们
Stay strong.
我会记住你们
Remember, pain's only in the mind.
进去！
Move along! Go!
快进去！
Troop, go!
快点！ 快点！
Move! Move!
史林特...
Splinter.
师父
Sensei.
Master.
让我帮你抬出来
Let's get him to the needle room.
货物已回收，我们正在路上
Package is secured. En route.
我们手上有三个，大概40分内可以抵达
In approximately 40 minutes.
把容器都准备好
Prepare the containment units.
这些乌龟体内
Inside those turtles
有这地球上最珍贵的物质
is the most precious compound on Earth,
那些变种基因
mutagen.
为了提取那些
And we will drain every last
我们会榨干他们身上每次一滴血
ounce of their blood to get it,
即便你们杀了他们我也无所谓
even if it kills them.
给我那个急救箱！ 就在架子上！
Get the first aid kit! On the shelf!
没事的，没事的
Hurry. Hurry.
拉斐尔？
Raphael?
我在这
I'm here.
你必须去救你的兄弟们
You must save your brothers.
阻止许瑞德
Stop Shredder.
师父...
Sensei.
有什么警报
It's some kind of tracker.
是太罗发过来的！
It's Donatello!
快去，拉斐尔
Go, Raphael.
我这就去救我的兄弟们
Let's go save my brothers.
我们还需要辆车
We need a ride.
奥尼尔！
O'Neil!
我需要你现在过来
Look, Vern, I need you to meet me
请10分钟之内到
at Cortlandt Alley in 10 minutes, please.
等等，为什么？
Wait, why?
我在电话里不能说
I can't talk to you about it on the phone.
你过来就对了
Just promise you're gonna be there.
你到底在说什么？你打过来...
What do you mean, you can't talk about... You called...
...我
...me.
好吧...你现在想见我了？
All right. Want me to meet you right now?
那我就陪你玩玩
I'll play your little game.
你怎么带这帽子？
What's with the hat?
我带帽子？
What is with the...
好吧...
I don't know,
就是想搞点噱头
it's a buddy of mine's. It's just a goof.
你要去哪？ 我们要去约会吗？
What do you want to do? You wanna head downtown?
萨克斯是为脚帮做事的
Eric Sacks is working with the head of the Foot Clan.
他刚来
They just kidnapped the vigilante turtles
抓走了乌龟们
to take them to the Sacks estate.
我们需要尽快赶过去
We need to go. Come on, Vern.
喔对对，乌龟们，我都忘了...
Right, right, right. The turtles. I forgot.
这实在是太让人难堪了，奥尼尔
This is getting embarrassing. O'Neil,
我们都是很不错的成年人
we're both consenting adults.
我们都长得不错 你肯定..条件更好...
We're both very good-looking. You're better, probably.
我的重点是...
That's up for debate.
我们出来约会
But the point is, we don't need to make up excuses
- 其实不需要找什么藉口 - 什么？
to hang out with each other. What?
想花更多时间和我待在一起， 我知道的，也这样想
You want to spend more time with me. I get it. I would too.
我们需要现在
We need to get to the Sacks estate
就赶紧赶去萨克斯的那边！
right now, Vern. Come on!
你一直跟我扯什么萨克斯的地方， 还有什么守护者
"The Sacks estate with the vigilante..."
- 什么... - 快开车！
What... Drive!
乌龟会说话
You're a talking turtle.
是的  我们是会说话的乌龟
Yeah. Yeah, I'm a talking turtle
而你是人类怪胎
and you're a human nerd.
知道了就快开车
Now that we got that out of the way, hit it.
我很抱歉刚刚的行为， 但是有个问题...
I've never been accused of being a nerd before, but...
对不起...
I'm sorry...
你是怎么...进来的...
How did you get in... How did he get in the...
喔 天啊
Oh, my.
Wow.
太难以置信了，你们看看你们自己
Unbelievable. Let me look at you.
一般人很难给我留下什么印象
I'm a hard guy to impress, but...
这实在是.....吓到我了...
This is just... Oh, my God.
Wow!
之后我们会把你们
And we were gonna use rabbits!
当兔子来实验，你们能想像吗？
Can you imagine that? All we were trying to do
我们所有想做的，就是创造一个， 万灵药
is create an antidote.
为了什么？
For what?
在说一遍我想要多听听你的声音
Say that again. I want to hear your voice.
为了什么？
For what?
Wow.
是这样的，我们原来有个计画
Well, uh, we had this plan.
一个我们准备重新开始进行的计画， 就在今天
A plan that we're ready to put back online today.
我会示范给你们看的，卡拉
I'll show you. Karai, um...
让他们看看
Show them.
抓住他
What?
你知道我自己的建筑  萨克斯大楼吧？
Do you know my building, Sacks Tower?
就在楼顶有巨大的建筑
Got that great big spire up on top?
那个建筑的里面...
That spire is filled...
装满了数吨的有毒化学物质
...with tons of chemical toxins.
不！ 不！
No! No!
也就是很残忍的东西
Bad stuff.
就像这样残忍
That kinda bad.
就在几小时之内
In a few hours,
许瑞德就会释放所有的有害物质
Shredder is going to unleash all that stuff
遍布整个城市
over the whole city. The initial death toll
而政府将会被这景象深深震撼
will shake world governments to their core.
在30天内
In 30 days,
纽约将会 成为一个彻底的隔离区
the city of New York will be a quarantine zone.
而这时, 我的公司就可以介入了
And that is where my company comes in.
我将会用这万灵药
I'm going to save everyone with the antidote
拯救美国人民于水火
that is made from the mutagen
而解药就是从你们的血液中， 抽取研制而来的
that is oozing through your blood.
然后政府就将会给萨克斯集团， 一张任我填写的支票
The government will then send Sacks Industry a blank check
之后我就会变富有， 非常的富有
and I'm going to be rich. Like, stupid rich.
许瑞德则会驱使这座城市， 按照我们的规则运作
Shredder will force this city to live under our rule.
到时候我们就是上帝
We will be gods.
我之前曾经想过进行训练...
Yeah, I've thought about...
不是说要成为忍者，但是...
not becoming a ninja, but I was doing a bunch of yoga
但是我有训练，比如说连续练习瑜伽10天...
for like, 10 days at one point, and, uh, I pulled a hamstring.
- 我们到了 - 就是那里
There's the gate right there. There it is.
就这样撞进去
Ram the gate.
" 撞进去 " ? 这是第6频道的财产阿
"Ram the gate"? This is Channel 6 property.
我说了冲进去！
I said ram the gate!
好吧，大家抓紧了！
All right, everybody, strap in!
喔 该死的！
Oh, shit!
上，上，上，上！
Go, go, go, go!
跟着我！
Follow me!
东西给我
I'll take this canister to New York
我带去纽约继续研究基因
to withdraw the mutagen.
确保你们把他们所有的血液都抽干
Make sure that you drain all their blood.
是时候干掉剩下的那个大家伙了
Time to take a bite out of the Big Apple.
嗨！ 滚离这里！
Hey! Get out of here!
李奥！
Leo!
来的真是时候
About time.
什么...
What the...
拉斐尔...
Raphael.
很高兴你能来这加入我们
Glad you could join us.
第四个笼子，已经为你准备好了
The fourth cage is for you.
这一下真够痛的，兄弟
That's harsh, man.
那只老鼠，根本没有把你们教好
The rat did not teach you well!
拉斐尔！
Raphael!
你...
You.
你专心跟我打
Focus on me.
四个会说话的乌龟
Three... Four total turtles.
打一个机器武士... 有何不可...
One's fighting a robot samurai. Why not?
多尼！
Donnie!
多尼！我应该怎么做
- 肾上腺素。 - 你说什么？
Adrenaline. What?
肾上腺素
Adrenaline.
没问题
All right. All right.
警告 - 心脏 心跳减慢
肾上腺素。
Adrenaline.
他这样会杀了他的
He's going to kill him.
警告 - 肾上腺素 过量风险
快起来阿！
Get up!
真的奏效了
It's working.
我觉得我们应该先回避一下
I think we should move.
哇现在感觉好爽阿
Oh! I feel really good right now! I feel like running!
我感觉好像在七重天
I feel like cleaning! Who wants to clean the dojo?
感觉像是上了天堂！
I'll clean the dojo!
嘿 拉斐尔还躺在那！
Endorphins! Endorphins!
嘿 拉斐尔！
We got to get Raph!
拉斐尔！ 拉斐尔！
Raph! Raph!
你没问题吗？ 你死吗？ 你没问题吗？
Are you okay? Are you dead? Are you okay?
快来 快走
Come on. Come on.
- 去哪？ - 去萨克斯大楼！
- Go where? - Sacks Tower!
在纽约
New York City! Times Square!
许瑞德去释放毒气去了！
Shredder's going to release a toxin!
他要让全城中毒！
It's gonna poison the whole city!
然后萨克斯要去卖解药！
And Sacks is gonna sell the antidote!
他说解药在我们的血液里 所以他现在就要过去那里了
That's in our blood! So we've got to get going now!
- 没错 - 让我们为了师父报仇
Good. Let's do it for  sensei.
好的，我们出发吧！
Okay. We're going!
所以人都冷静，希望就在我们身上了
Everybody calm down! Look how calm I am!
我们速度得快点了，我们走
We got to move. Let's go!
萨克斯坐直升机走了！
Sacks is airborne!
他飞过去只要19分钟！
Flight time to Manhattan, 19 minutes!
我们先从这离开，多尼！
Get us out of here, Donnie!
扫描中
不是吧!，敌人来了！
Oh, my gosh, they have guns!
快趴下！
Get down!
你们没事吧？
Ha! Are you guys okay?
原来我们还能防弹
We're bulletproof.
水啦！
Sweet!
我们要抢到那辆卡车！
Advance and engage!
你能驾驶那卡车吗？
Can you drive that truck?
耶！
Yeah!
好的，准备，拉斐尔, 好了吗？
We're on Raph. Ready?
快来！
Come on!
所有人都上卡车，我们得出发了！
Everybody in the truck! We gotta go, go, go! Move!
你会开这玩意对吧？
Vern, you know how to drive this, right?
是的是的, 所以我要
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Just got to hotwire this thing, I guess.
把下面线拆了点火就能走了
Classic blue wire/red wire situation.
- 钥匙！ - 是的
Keys! Yeah.
钥匙比较好
Keys are better.
- 快开车！ - 我上面！
Drive! I'm on it!
我需要的只是后座 那一堆会开车会说话的乌龟
That's all I need is a backseat-driving talking turtle!
- 我们出发！ - 快追！
- Let's go! - Move!
- 往你们正前方开 - 收到
- Jackal-One-Tango, on your 12! -  Copy that.
抱歉之前怀疑你
I shouldn't have doubted you.
我还以为你疯了
Sorry I didn't stick up for you.
不过这实在很疯狂
I can't believe that you're not crazy! How crazy is that?
目标在正前方！
Target, 12 o'clock!
伙伴们我们现在到底是去哪？
Where are we going, guys?
多尼，最好回到曼哈顿的路线是什么？
Donnie, what's the fastest way back to Manhattan?
我们只要沿着目前路线前进
We just need to stay on this road.
如果能到达
If we can get to the maintenance hatch
山下那个维修机房
at the bottom of the hill,
那有个下水道就距离这里2.4公里
there's a sewer line 2.4 miles from here.
米奇！ 我们得让他们知道一下！
Mikey! Let them know up there!
我上来了！
I'm on it!
哦，不是吧...
Oh, no.
凡恩，快快快，往右开！
Vern, go, go, go, go, go!
我上面！
I'm on it!
停止！
Stop!
凡恩，快踩煞车！
Vern, hit the brakes!
错误的方法！ 错误的方法！
Wrong way! Wrong way!
他们下去了！ 快追！
Go around! Go, go, go!
李奥，躲开！
Leo, move, move!
什么？
What?
Opposite, opposite, opposite!
哦，不！
Oh, no!
我们偏离了多远？
How far off course are we?
我们现在绝对是在抄近路
Actually, we're on a bit of a shortcut.
但是我们其实是需要从这山上下去
But we need to keep going down.
我意思是直直地往下走
Straight down.
嗨！
Hey!
尽量...保持
Just keep
向前...开！
going straight!
你好阿美女
What's up, angel cakes?
该死！
Fire!
伙伴们! 李奥，有麻烦了！
Guys, Leo's in trouble!
我的壳刚才破了
My shell's cracked. Just tape it up.
- 这次得靠你了 - 看来我得出一次锋头了
Allow me to be the bad-ass for once.
抓住，李奥，别害怕，我来帮你了
Hang on, Leo. Disengaging.
我其实一直都想试着这么玩一下
God, I've always wanted to try this.
我抓住你了，兄弟， 搞定一个，还剩下两个
I got you, brother. One car down, two to go.
米奇！
Mikey!
- 好吧  坚持住 - 我这就来了！
All right, that's it. I'll take it from here!
Whoo-hoo!
伙伴们，我正在开车呢！
Raph, I'm driving! Yeah!
Whoo-hoo!
奥尼尔，你在干嘛？
O'Neil, what are you doing?
很好继续拍，不要漏掉任何镜头
Yeah, that's good. Make sure you're getting everything.
凡恩！
Vern!
奥尼尔！ 把手给我！
O'Neil! Give me your arm!
凡恩！
Vern!
雪崩来了！
Avalanche!
Whoa!
快点李奥，快点醒来！
Come on, Leo, wake up!
如果你醒来
Yeah! If you wake up,
任何都你说了算！
I promise to do anything you say!
许瑞德的直升机
Guys! Shredder's chopper is 20 miles
现在距离纽约那边还有32公里！
outside of New York City airspace!
谢谢你的直升机状态更新，多尼
Thanks for the traffic update, Donnie.
现在的重点是我们之后要干嘛？
You doing sports and weather next?
坏消息
If you're gonna be nasty about it
是53秒内
then I guess you don't want to know
你会看到悬崖
that there's a 500-foot drop-off in 53 seconds!
你是说有悬崖...
Are you saying there's...
我醒过来了！
A cliff!
我们得把爱普莉尔救出来， 把你的手给我
We gotta get April out of there! Raph, heads up!
别忘记还有一个老男人！
Don't forget that old guy!
- 李奥 - 嘿，计画有变
Hi. Change of plans. Oh, come on.
- 喔，不是吧 - 快趴下
Guys, get down! Get down!
还有12秒我们就要掉下去了！
Twelve seconds and we're going over!
嘿 多尼，快玩那招花俏的弹射技！
Hey, Donnie, do that fancy slingshot thing!
我得把那台车给解决了！
We got to take Little Miss Sunshine out!
抓紧了！
Batter up!
快抓住绳子！
Grab on.
米奇！ 抓住绳子！
Mikey! Grab the cable!
我抓到它！ 我抓到它！
I got it! I got it!
等等！ 等等！
Hold on! Hold on!
哦，不！
Oh, no!
不，不，不！
No, no, no!
哦，不...
Oh, no...
李奥，爱普莉尔...
Poor Leo, April...
还有那个不知名的男人...
And that other guy.
他们还那么年轻， 那么漂亮
They were so young, so beautiful.
- 那么漂亮 - 别废话了，蠢蛋
They ain't dead, numb nuts.
喔，你们还活着阿
Oh. Right on.
我希望你的壳里藏着一个降落伞
I hope you got a parachute under that shell.
- 伙伴们！ - 那是维修机房！
Hey, guys! It's the maintenance hatch!
真是一次绝妙的反击行动阿！
Our ticket home!
别废话了，拉我们上去！
A little help, please!
伙伴们，我们有麻烦了, 许瑞德已经到纽约了
Guys, we gotta hustle. Shredder's over New York City!
老师，我们还有4分钟抵达
Sensei, the mutagen is four minutes out.
正按照计画前进
Moving forward as planned.
请乘客
Please keep your arms and legs
请勿把手脚伸出壳外
inside the shell at all times.
另一则更新
Satellite imagery shows
许瑞德已经在萨克斯大楼顶端了
Shredder's reached the top of Sacks Tower.
如果他释放了毒气那城市就完了
If that's where he's releasing the toxin from...
那城市就完了！
It's gonna spread all over the city!
我们得...
We need to...
好了，都听着！
...break a left!
我们需要找到通往屋顶的电梯
We gotta find the elevators and get up to the roof.
你们离开这里， 跑到安全的距离外躲起来
You guys get out of here. Get to a safe distance.
不，不，我们可以去找萨克斯
No, no, we can go find Sacks
然后得到解药，就当作备用计画
and get our hands on the mutagen as a contingency plan,
就是以防万一
just in case... You know.
谢谢你们的那份勇气
Thanks for the vote of confidence.
如果我们回不来， 把万灵药带去给史林特
If we don't make it back, bring the mutagen to Splinter.
万灵药可以救活他
It can save his life.
萨克斯在36楼的实验室
Sacks's laboratory's on the 36th floor.
我已经关掉所有保安系统了
I've already disabled the security system.
对了  ...
Oh, and, uh...
祝好运
Good luck!
如果我回不来，你要记得我，爱普莉尔
If I don't return, remember me, April.
你可以永远在你心里
You can always find me
找到我
in here.
我们也走吧
You're a complicated chick.
很好
Yeah.
电梯就在转角！
Elevator's just around this corner!
大家听好了
All right, guys, listen up.
照我的计画就不会失败
We stick to my plan and we won't fail.
三秒后冲出去
Fan out in three, two, one.
Whoa.
那里不是电梯啦
Not the elevator.
真的不是
Nope.
第一个容器开始注入解药
The first vial is filling with antidote now.
开始启动毒气释放程序
Initiating the toxin release procedure.
嘻哈米奇
MC Mikey.
嘻哈
MC
准备， 摆好阵仗！
Ready, stance!
嘿 米奇，记得那
Hey, Mikey, remember that thing you used to say
你记得小时候喊的那句话吗？
when we were kids?
你要我保证别在说的
You made me promise never to say it again.
忘了那回事
Forget about that.
想不想来喊一下？
Still got one in the tank?
我肖想很久了
I've been holding it in for years.
兄弟们，我们需要...
Guys, we need a plan!
- 卡哇邦嘎！ - 兄弟们 你们要干嘛
Cowabunga!
李奥！
Leo!
我们这有情况
Yeah, we got a 10-10.
楼顶有残骸掉落
Debris falling from the building.
快点
Come on.
我来搞定这个，伙伴们
I got this, guys! I'll take him!
来吧！
Come on!
哦，不，你没有！
Oh, no, you don't!
说真的
Seriously,
你们俩...
you two...
真是让人尊敬阿，真的
You're adorable, really.
我都能感受到你们的魄力
I could just pinch your cheeks!
兄弟们， 他来了，他来了！
Ugh, guys, he's coming, he's coming!
兄弟们！
Guys!
多尼！
Donnie!
抓紧，抓紧！
Come on, come on!
抓紧阿，李奥！
Hold on, Leo!
我充分理解你想为你爸爸报仇的心情
I understand a girl with dead daddy issues.
但是你阻止不了我
I do. But you're not gonna stop me.
这只不过是
This is history
历史重演而已
repeating itself.
你的父亲也想阻止我， 爱普莉尔，就像你现在一样
Your father walked in on me, April, just like you did.
我不得不开枪杀了他
It took a few less bullets to take him down, though.
你杀了我父亲
You killed my father.
快点！ 快点！
Move! Move!
快，快，快！
Go, go, go!
来吧，兄弟们！
Come on, guys!
抓到你了！
Got you!
够了没，这堂课已经结束了
Enough. The lesson is over.
我们被扁的太惨了
Ugh! We're getting our asses kicked out there.
剩下50多秒的时间毒气就要释放了
We only got 50 more seconds before the toxin's released.
Hey.
你们谁想玩巴巴克啊？
Who wants to play Buck-Buck?
巴巴克？
Buck-Buck?
- 什么？ - 你说什么？
What? Buck-Buck. Tony-on-a-Pony.
Some people call it Johnnie-on-a-Rock.
等等...
Wait.
对
Yeah.
让我们来玩巴巴克
Let's play Buck-Buck.
- 但是我们为什么要... - 不...
But why would we... No.
我会按照李奥的做
We do what Leo says.
我们是一体的
Lead the way.
奥尼尔！
O'Neil!
Argh!
Hmm.
Oh!
卡哇邦嘎！
Cowabunga.
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
把万灵药带上，去找人来帮忙
Look, just go get some help and take the mutagen with you.
走阿，快点走！
Just go. Go! No!
这是我难得耍帅的一天， 可是我起不来
Just another day in the life of a man of action.
哦不，好痛
Ow. No, I'm not getting up.
你知道怎么解除这东西吗？
You know how to use this thing?
这是古董了
It's a simple command-line interface.
这东西
No one's used this code in 15 years.
是15年前的技术了
I mean, I've read about it online.
我只有在网路看过...
But these kind of things take time.
这很困难阿
Thinking there was no way I'd ever be in a position
我从来就没有...
where the fate of an entire city...
我去帮你争取一些时间
I'll buy you some time.
5秒之后将释放毒气
Toxin disbursement
在五，四
in five, four,
三
three,
二
two...
搞定，危机解除！ 你们争取的时间很宝贵
Bam! System disabled! Who wants Italian?
为你们每个人喝采！
I'm buying! Tiramisu for everybody! Ah!
Ah.
这座塔要倒了！
Fall in!
等等！撑住！撑住！
Hold on! Hold it! Hold it!
如果毒气瓶落地摔破
If the spire falls and the toxin makes ground impact,
也会污染城市！
it'll contaminate a 10-block radius!
我们能把它这样守住的机率有多大？
What are the odds of us stopping that from happening?
0.0000000000003%!
Uh, 0.00000000003%!
那我还是赌一把吧 现在开始所以人坚守住，都不能动
I'll take it. Nobody moves, no matter what.
我说，李奥...
But, Leo...
我说了所有人都不许动！
I said nobody moves!
李奥，让我去！
Leo, I'm letting go!
Ah!
许瑞德！
Shredder!
这是唯一剩下的！
This is all that's left!
又是你这小女孩
Little girl.
这是我的东西
That belongs to me.
撑住了，要撑住阿
Hold on! Hold on! Hold it!
退后！所有人都退后！
Get back! All the way back!
爱普莉尔！
April!
来吧, 兄弟们！
Come on, guys!
Ah!
爱普莉尔！
April!
抓到你了，拉斐尔！
Got you, Raph!
抓紧了！抓紧了！ 爱普莉尔！
Hold on! Hold on! April!
我抓到你了
I got you.
把我甩过去！
Swing me towards him!
照她说的做！
Do it!
李奥！
Leo!
终于搞定了，就是这样
That's my girl.
我觉得我们大限将至！
I think this is it, guys!
有人有什么遗言要说的吗？
Does anyone have anything they want to say?
多尼？
Donnie?
每天早上
I'm the one who licks the icing
我都会偷舔糖霜
off the Pop-Tarts every morning
再把他们放回原处
and puts them back in the box.
不，不，不，不！
No, no, no, no!
我还是青少年不想那么早死啊
I so did not understand the ending of  Lost.
拉斐尔？
Raph?
我只是想说
I just, uh...
如果这是我们大家最后一刻
If this is our last moment together,
我只想让你们知道我很抱歉
I just want you guys to know I'm sorry.
我很抱歉，我不应该对你们那么严苛的
I'm sorry I was so hard on you.
每次我逼迫你们的时候...
Every time I pushed you, I... I threatened you,
我朝你怒吼，逼你们突破极限
I yelled at you, I pushed you beyond your limits,
只是因为我相信你们！
it was because I believe in you!
相信你们每个人！
I believe in each one of you!
我相信你们的信念
I believe in your spirit and your intelligence
精神和潜能
and your potential.
而每次我说着要离开
And every time I talked about walking away,
是因为我很害怕
it was because I was scared!
我只是觉得
I just didn't think I was good enough
我逐渐不配站在你们身旁
to stand next to you
称呼你们为兄弟， 我必须告诉你们
and call you brothers and say to you
我爱你们！
I love you!
我非常爱你们每个人
I love you guys so much!
拉斐尔...？
Raph?
我们成功了
We made it.
你在哭吗？
Are you crying?
才不是，只是灰尘太多了
No, ding-dong. It's just a little dusty out here.
好了，
Okay, the mutagen is now
现在万灵药进入他的血液了
entering his bloodstream.
史林特师父？
Master Splinter?
没事情发生
Nothing's happening.
为什么他还不见效果？
Why isn't it working yet?
米奇...
Mikey...
米奇，靠近点听我说
Huh? Mikey, come closer.
- 他说什么？ - 他说什么？
What did he say? What did he say?
他说: 你别跪在我的胸口上
He said, "Please get your knee off my chest."
师父！
Sensei!
你还活着！
You're alive!
它见效了！
It worked!
这都是我的错
I'm sorry. This was all my fault.
你是对的， 我们还没准备好
You were right. We weren't ready.
不对，是我并没有准备好
No.
去做好准备让你们离开
It was I who wasn't ready to let you go.
所有你们需要做的
All you needed was to discover
就是发现在你们身上潜在的真正力量
that your true power lies in believing in one another.
看吧她来了
There she is.
纽约的秘密武器你好
New York's secret weapon.
你的手怎么样了，凡恩
How's your arm, Vern?
是阿， 如果我不选择冲上去的话，也就不会受伤了
Well, it wouldn't be much use in a fight.
虽然我以前的确不会这样鲁莽
Not that I was much use before, but...
- 你有辆新车了 - 是阿
Did you get a new car? Yeah.
这辆是我们的新的新闻车
You're looking at the new Fenwick Express.
看起来不错吧
Pretty sweet, huh?
还改装了一下
Kind of an upgrade.
我想我需要在除了我工作的车之外
I figured I'd need new wheels
自己也弄一辆新车来开开
after my old work vehicle went boom.
第6频道给了我这个
Yeah, Channel 6 gave it to me.
他们说千万别刮花了
They said don't put a scratch on it,
它的速度是原本的两倍多
but, like, lightning's going to strike twice?
所以你把我叫到这里是为什么
So, is that why you called me here,
就为了聊你的新车？
to talk about your new car?
我想你不是很热衷于
I know that you're not exactly
被请客吃饭的那一类女孩
a fancy restaurant kind of girl, so I figured
所以我觉得
a creepy underpass in an abandoned neighborhood
约你来这个废弃的工地
in the middle of the night was more your speed.
会让我看起来很更酷
I wanted you to be comfortable.
爱普莉尔爱普莉尔爱普莉尔，DJ米奇来了！
DJ Mikey in the house!
你们几个在这干嘛？
What are you guys doing here?
我发觉我们还欠你个人情， 帮我们保守我们的秘密
We figured we owed you a thanks for keeping our secret.
如果你把我们的消息卖给人类， 你可以大赚一笔，
You had a lot to gain from telling people about us,
但是你保护了我们
but you had our backs.
是阿 朋友就是用来彼此守护的， 拉斐尔
Yeah, 'cause that's what family's for, Raph.
你们也弄一辆车了？
So you guys are driving now?
里面有液晶电视
Yeah, man. I pimped this bad boy out.
制冰机
Got a 42-inch plasma with the
7.1杜比环绕音响
NBA package, shave ice machine,
NBA篮球门票
7.1 digital surround sound.
看看这东西，兄弟
Check the bass, bra.
Uh-oh.
Ooh.
是我的错，我没搞清楚要按哪个钮
My bad. I'm still figuring out the buttons.
这是我的新车阿！
That was my new Fenwick Express!
我才刚拿到它阿
I just... I just got that.
我们该走了，需要载你回家吗？
We better get out of here. Want a ride home?
不用了...我和他坐地铁回家吧
You know what? I think we're gonna take the subway.
我们坐地铁
We're going to take the subway.
你确定吗？
You sure?
我特地为你做了一首歌
I got a real nice song that's all cued up.
为了你这个特别的女孩
- It's special, girl. - No, don't.
- 为了我们俩 - 别搞了 米奇
- For us. - Come on, Mikey.
- 不，不，不， -女孩 听听我的承诺
No, no, no, Mikey, you promised.
- 虽然我很花心, 自从遇到你 - 停止唱歌
? Imagine me and you I do
我就想唱歌给你听, 请你别怀疑
? I think about you day and night It's only right
现在就我就在这里
? To think about... ?
希望你会接受我！
I'm making really good headway!
快点闭嘴, 米奇！
Shut up, Mikey!
噢…已经决定了
? I can't see me loving nobody but you
我这一生非你不娶
? For all my life
你的笑容
? When you're with me, baby
美得就像晴空万里
? The skies'll be blue For all my life! ?
**********